On the Eastern front in 1943, the German soldiers no longer had any ideals.
They were not fighting for the Party—but for their lives!
Cross of Iron is a drama, action, history film directed by Sam Peckinpah.
It is 1943, and the German army—ravaged and demoralised—is
hastily retreating from the Russian front.
In the midst of the madness, conflict brews between the aristocratic yet ultimately
pusillanimous Captain Stransky and the courageous Corporal Steiner.
Stransky is the only man who believes that the Third Reich is
still vastly superior to the Russian army.
However, within his pompous persona lies a quivering coward who longs for
the Iron Cross so that he can return to Berlin a hero.
Steiner, on the other hand is cynical, defiantly non-conformist and more concerned with the safety of his
own men rather than the horde of military decorations offered to him by his superiors.
Unteroffizier / Feldwebel Rolf Steiner, played by James Coburn.
Hauptmann Stransky, played by Maximilian Schell.
Oberst Brandt, played by James Mason.
Hauptmann Kiesel, played by David Warner.
Unteroffizier Krüger, played by Klaus Löwitsch.
Gefreiter Kern, played by Vadim Glowna.
Cross of Iron (German: Steiner – Das Eiserne Kreuz, lit.
"Steiner – The Iron Cross") is a 1977 war film directed by Sam Peckinpah,
featuring James Coburn, Maximilian Schell, James Mason, and David Warner.
Set on the Eastern Front in World War II during the Soviets' Caucasus operations against the German Kuban bridgehead on the Taman Peninsula in late 1943, the film focuses
on the class conflict between a newly arrived, aristocratic Prussian officer who covets winning the Iron Cross and a cynical, battle-hardened infantry NCO.
An international co-production between British and West German financiers,
the film's exteriors were shot on location in Yugoslavia.
The film explores themes of hostility, world war ii,
battle for power, troops, commander.
The tone is emotional.